<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>itsmesanjo@gmail.com &#8211; Review on Things</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/author/itsmesanjogmail-com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings</link>
	<description>by Sanjo</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 19:28:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cropped-ROT_Logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>itsmesanjo@gmail.com &#8211; Review on Things</title>
	<link>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How are NFTs transforming Digital Art? #CryptoArt</title>
		<link>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/05/08/what-is-the-future-of-nftsnon-fungible-tokens-as-a-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/05/08/what-is-the-future-of-nftsnon-fungible-tokens-as-a-technology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[itsmesanjo@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 09:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloackchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crptoart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT bad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT Good]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non fungible tokens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What are NFTs? To understand Non Fungible Tokens, we have to first understand Fungibility. If you can interchange a commodity with another identical item, that [...]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4><strong>What are NFTs?</strong></h4>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-1024x994.png" alt="" class="wp-image-15" width="377" height="365" srcset="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-1024x994.png 1024w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-300x291.png 300w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-768x746.png 768w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-1080x1049.png 1080w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1.png 1313w" sizes="(max-width: 377px) 100vw, 377px" /></figure></div>



<p>To understand Non Fungible Tokens, we have to first understand Fungibility. If you can interchange a commodity with another identical item, that commodity becomes fungible. For example a 10 dollar bill is equivalent to 10 one-dollar bills. Thus an item becomes Non-Fungible when it becomes unique or hard to replace with an identical item. In NFT, each token is unique, because there is a unique asset behind it. Thus if an artist turns his/her art into an NFT and puts it on sale, no other NFTs become equal to this as there is no other such piece of art.</p>



<p>Some traits of NFTs are:</p>



<ul><li>they represent unique assets</li><li>one cannot divde a NFT into smaller parts like a dollar or bitcoin, which are fungible</li><li>they are highly traceable</li></ul>



<h4><strong>How it works?</strong></h4>



<p>Have you heard of smart contracts? Smart contracts are digital contracts that enable credible transactions without any third-party involvement. These transactions can be tracked and are irreversible too. These contracts are stored on blockchain technology, a decentralized digital ledger used to record all transactions.</p>



<p>These smart contracts are the backbone of NFTs. Thus ownership details, to all the exchange/ transfer details all can be easily tracked to identify their authenticity.</p>



<h4><strong>What is its future?</strong></h4>



<p>The headlines of a digital drawing of a simple cat getting sold for millions of dollars might have bought people to the limelight use case of selling art digitally. But that is just one form of its use case.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-08-150023.png" alt="" class="wp-image-16" width="358" height="263" srcset="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-08-150023.png 772w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-08-150023-300x220.png 300w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-08-150023-768x564.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 358px) 100vw, 358px" /></figure></div>



<p>I would implore you to try out <a href="https://www.ecomi.com/">Ecomi</a>, <a href="https://aavegotchi.com/">Aavegotchi</a>, <a href="https://nbatopshot.com/">Topshots</a> or the gaming NFTs. Also, you can check NFT marketplace like <a href="https://www.piction.com/site/">Piction</a>. And there are countless things that being build based on its core property that is &#8220;Non-Fungibility&#8221; which gives the item its stamp of uniqueness.</p>



<p>For artists who create digital assets, it is very hard to sell them easily, as all digital art can easily be copied in one form or the other. With technology like NFTs, it gives a mark of authenticity to it, which is really useful for people in this field. This makes digital art worth being a collector&#8217;s item. Which makes the value of an item go very high, which earlier was not possible.</p>



<p>Smart contracts which support NFTs have a wide range of use cases ranging from legal documents to supply chain. Thus the future of NFTs as technology is wide and growing.</p>



<h4><strong>What is the downside?</strong></h4>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-17" width="351" height="351" srcset="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-300x300.jpg 300w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-150x150.jpg 150w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-768x768.jpg 768w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-1080x1080.jpg 1080w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /></figure></div>



<p>Ecological factor. The backbone of NFTs that is the smart contract is the main culprit here. Smart contracts employ miners who have to provide computing power to solve those complex mathematical problems(Proof-of-Work (PoW)) which makes those smart contracts unique. But the energy these computers pull is on a high scale. To imagine this scale let&#8217;s take the example of the “Space Cat,” an NFT that’s basically a GIF of a cat in a rocket heading to the Moon. Space Cat’s carbon footprint is equivalent to an EU resident’s electricity usage for two months. You can read more about such alarming figures at <a href="https://cryptoart.wtf/">cryptoart.wtf.</a></p>



<p>This as such is not a problem that NFTs created, it is a problem that already existed with blockchain technology. Some NFT stores are claiming to equate the CO2 emissions by planting more trees. In theory, it sounds good but is not something that can easily be compensated like that. Only technology advancements in processor technology to create more energy-efficient ones can solve this issue on a large scale.</p>



<p>Do check out this article to learn more: <a href="https://github.com/memo/eco-nft">A guide to more sustainable CryptoArt</a></p>



<h4><strong>Ending thoughts!</strong></h4>



<p>NFTs are great for artists to create value out of their digital art, for collectors it opens a marketplace to collect digital art which can verify its authenticity, which in turn raises the value of the piece for the artists. But at present dealing with NFTs is a pricey affair in terms of the ecological factor. So let&#8217;s wait for the technology to evolve more efficiently.</p>



<p>Do share your views in the comments? More than happy to hear them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/05/08/what-is-the-future-of-nftsnon-fungible-tokens-as-a-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should you get a credit card in 2021?</title>
		<link>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/04/21/should-you-get-a-credit-card-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/04/21/should-you-get-a-credit-card-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[itsmesanjo@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 09:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benefits of credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit cards india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creditcard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indian credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Should you]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/?p=5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thinking of getting a credit card? Let me give you some pros and cons of getting a credit card. I am not associated with any [...]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Thinking of getting a credit card? Let me give you some pros and cons of getting a credit card. I am not associated with any credit card agency nor a financial advisor. I am just putting out this article as I get a lot of queries from my friends on whether credit cards are worth it or not. My usual answer is:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>YES, it has a lot to offer if you are good with your financial budgeting and NO if you are not.</p></blockquote>



<p>Yes, that&#8217;s all. That is the answer to the question. But if you like to hear more about the perks of having a credit card over a debit card, do keep reading.</p>



<p>A credit card is technically very similar to debit card and the main difference being you are not paying upfront the amount you shopped for, its more like a &#8220;Buy Now Pay Later&#8221; policy.</p>



<h4><strong>Why should I use Credit Card?</strong></h4>



<p>Everyone who has opened a bank account will mostly be having their own debit card. Then why would one manage one more card? Here are some benefits of credit card over debit card.</p>



<ol><li><strong>Credit History? CIBIL Score</strong>: In India or around the world, credit card is one of the best ways to create a good Credit History(or a CIBIL score), which helps in quick approval of loans such as personal loans or home loans and even to get a better interest rate deal. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, just getting a credit card won&#8217;t get you a good credit score, there are different parameters like how timely you pay your bills, etc.</li><li><strong>Fraud Protection:</strong> If any fraud/unauthorized transactions occur on your credit card it&#8217;s not your liability (subject to TnC of course). As soon as you encounter one, you should alert your card company to block your card. Rest all the card company takes care of, as the money from your end is safe and not lost, what is lost is the credit(basically, money from the card issuer). Thus these companies usually provide higher grade of security offerings to these credit accounts. Thus it is always better to use credit cards, especially for online transactions.</li><li><strong>Interest-Free Period</strong>. Most credit cards provide you interest-free period of 45-50 days. Your bills are generated monthly only. Thus even if you buy something now u will mostly have to pay within 20-50 days depending on your date of purchase and billing cycle. If you are using other forms of payment you are losing this amount upfront. In credit cards case, the money is still in your account, which can earn you interest based on your saving account scheme.</li><li><strong>Short Term Loan / No cost EMIs</strong>: If you plan your billing cycles properly, Credit Cards can also help when you are in a Cash Crunch situation, especially during month-ends when you are eagerly waiting for the salary credited SMS and don&#8217;t really want to bother your friends for a loan. Such short term loans can be taken care by credit cards. In situations when you want to buy your dream gadgets or your dream phone, you could use EMI options available, and in some cards, No Cost EMIs are also available, thus reducing the burden on your monthly budget.</li><li><strong>Tracking your monthly expenses</strong>: Credit cards are billed monthly. Thus you receive monthly expense statements which usually equates to your monthly expense if all your expenses were through your credit card.</li><li><strong>Offers/ reward points and more</strong>: Fuel Surcharge waivers, free Airport Lounge access, extra discounts or offers on ecommerce sites, etc are the cherry on top. Also, there are rewards even for paying your credit card bill through apps like Cred. You can use <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://app.cred.club/spQx/d18ba9c2" target="_blank">my referral link</a> to join Cred.</li></ol>



<h4>Is it all sunshine and rainbows?</h4>



<p>Every coin has two sides, credit cards have got their disadvantages too.</p>



<ol><li><strong>Chances of overspending</strong>: As money doesn&#8217;t easily get debited from your bank account it gives a false sense that you are not overspending. It is very important that always consider credit card as another debit card and spend only that much you have kept in your monthly budget for expenses.</li><li><strong>Higher Interest Rate and Late Payment fee</strong>: Be cautious that after the interest-free period the interest rate charged is usually very high. So it&#8217;s very important to pay your credit card bills before the due date in full otherwise, you will end up in a big debt trap and that&#8217;s what Credit card companies want. Turning ON auto pay for credit cards helps a lot for these situations. There are also annual card fees depending on your card, which mostly get waived off after a particular amount thus urging people to spend more.</li><li><strong>Financial Privacy</strong>: These cards come with an undisclosed clause of foregoing your financial privacy, as all your expense history is recorded through your card usage by these companies. Which is analyzed and used to learn your financial patterns, spending cycle, interests etc. But this is the case with any form of cashless medium. This is one of the main reasons why big conglomerates such as Facebook, Google are after India&#8217;s UPI system and its 1.4 billion market.</li></ol>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woman-hand-putting-money-coin-into-glass-jar-saving-money_59017-33.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-31" width="348" height="261" srcset="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woman-hand-putting-money-coin-into-glass-jar-saving-money_59017-33.jpg 626w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woman-hand-putting-money-coin-into-glass-jar-saving-money_59017-33-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 348px) 100vw, 348px" /></figure></div>



<h4><strong>Rules to abide by</strong></h4>



<p>If you do decide to use credit cards, remember these simple rules:</p>



<ul><li>Keep track of all your purchases.</li><li>Don&#8217;t spend outside your budget.</li><li>Pay off your balance in full, on all of your credit cards at the end of each month.</li><li>Don&#8217;t loan your credit or give out your credit card information to anyone.</li></ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>If your credit card is giving some extra perks which I have not listed here, do comment it down below. Would love to hear them!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/04/21/should-you-get-a-credit-card-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
