<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>crypto &#8211; Review on Things</title>
	<atom:link href="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/tag/crypto/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings</link>
	<description>by Sanjo</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 19:28:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cropped-ROT_Logo-32x32.png</url>
	<title>crypto &#8211; Review on Things</title>
	<link>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How are NFTs transforming Digital Art? #CryptoArt</title>
		<link>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/05/08/what-is-the-future-of-nftsnon-fungible-tokens-as-a-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/05/08/what-is-the-future-of-nftsnon-fungible-tokens-as-a-technology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[itsmesanjo@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 09:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloackchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crptoart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT bad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT Good]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non fungible tokens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What are NFTs? To understand Non Fungible Tokens, we have to first understand Fungibility. If you can interchange a commodity with another identical item, that [...]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4><strong>What are NFTs?</strong></h4>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-1024x994.png" alt="" class="wp-image-15" width="377" height="365" srcset="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-1024x994.png 1024w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-300x291.png 300w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-768x746.png 768w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1-1080x1049.png 1080w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/1_rx8odLIf652b_4pm21MAtw-1.png 1313w" sizes="(max-width: 377px) 100vw, 377px" /></figure></div>



<p>To understand Non Fungible Tokens, we have to first understand Fungibility. If you can interchange a commodity with another identical item, that commodity becomes fungible. For example a 10 dollar bill is equivalent to 10 one-dollar bills. Thus an item becomes Non-Fungible when it becomes unique or hard to replace with an identical item. In NFT, each token is unique, because there is a unique asset behind it. Thus if an artist turns his/her art into an NFT and puts it on sale, no other NFTs become equal to this as there is no other such piece of art.</p>



<p>Some traits of NFTs are:</p>



<ul><li>they represent unique assets</li><li>one cannot divde a NFT into smaller parts like a dollar or bitcoin, which are fungible</li><li>they are highly traceable</li></ul>



<h4><strong>How it works?</strong></h4>



<p>Have you heard of smart contracts? Smart contracts are digital contracts that enable credible transactions without any third-party involvement. These transactions can be tracked and are irreversible too. These contracts are stored on blockchain technology, a decentralized digital ledger used to record all transactions.</p>



<p>These smart contracts are the backbone of NFTs. Thus ownership details, to all the exchange/ transfer details all can be easily tracked to identify their authenticity.</p>



<h4><strong>What is its future?</strong></h4>



<p>The headlines of a digital drawing of a simple cat getting sold for millions of dollars might have bought people to the limelight use case of selling art digitally. But that is just one form of its use case.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-08-150023.png" alt="" class="wp-image-16" width="358" height="263" srcset="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-08-150023.png 772w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-08-150023-300x220.png 300w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screenshot-2021-05-08-150023-768x564.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 358px) 100vw, 358px" /></figure></div>



<p>I would implore you to try out <a href="https://www.ecomi.com/">Ecomi</a>, <a href="https://aavegotchi.com/">Aavegotchi</a>, <a href="https://nbatopshot.com/">Topshots</a> or the gaming NFTs. Also, you can check NFT marketplace like <a href="https://www.piction.com/site/">Piction</a>. And there are countless things that being build based on its core property that is &#8220;Non-Fungibility&#8221; which gives the item its stamp of uniqueness.</p>



<p>For artists who create digital assets, it is very hard to sell them easily, as all digital art can easily be copied in one form or the other. With technology like NFTs, it gives a mark of authenticity to it, which is really useful for people in this field. This makes digital art worth being a collector&#8217;s item. Which makes the value of an item go very high, which earlier was not possible.</p>



<p>Smart contracts which support NFTs have a wide range of use cases ranging from legal documents to supply chain. Thus the future of NFTs as technology is wide and growing.</p>



<h4><strong>What is the downside?</strong></h4>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-17" width="351" height="351" srcset="https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-300x300.jpg 300w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-150x150.jpg 150w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-768x768.jpg 768w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516-1080x1080.jpg 1080w, https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GettyImages_1230723516.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /></figure></div>



<p>Ecological factor. The backbone of NFTs that is the smart contract is the main culprit here. Smart contracts employ miners who have to provide computing power to solve those complex mathematical problems(Proof-of-Work (PoW)) which makes those smart contracts unique. But the energy these computers pull is on a high scale. To imagine this scale let&#8217;s take the example of the “Space Cat,” an NFT that’s basically a GIF of a cat in a rocket heading to the Moon. Space Cat’s carbon footprint is equivalent to an EU resident’s electricity usage for two months. You can read more about such alarming figures at <a href="https://cryptoart.wtf/">cryptoart.wtf.</a></p>



<p>This as such is not a problem that NFTs created, it is a problem that already existed with blockchain technology. Some NFT stores are claiming to equate the CO2 emissions by planting more trees. In theory, it sounds good but is not something that can easily be compensated like that. Only technology advancements in processor technology to create more energy-efficient ones can solve this issue on a large scale.</p>



<p>Do check out this article to learn more: <a href="https://github.com/memo/eco-nft">A guide to more sustainable CryptoArt</a></p>



<h4><strong>Ending thoughts!</strong></h4>



<p>NFTs are great for artists to create value out of their digital art, for collectors it opens a marketplace to collect digital art which can verify its authenticity, which in turn raises the value of the piece for the artists. But at present dealing with NFTs is a pricey affair in terms of the ecological factor. So let&#8217;s wait for the technology to evolve more efficiently.</p>



<p>Do share your views in the comments? More than happy to hear them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/05/08/what-is-the-future-of-nftsnon-fungible-tokens-as-a-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
