<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Review on Things</title>
	<atom:link href="https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings</link>
	<description>by Sanjo</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 09:11:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Should you get a credit card in 2021?</title>
		<link>https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/04/21/should-you-get-a-credit-card-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/04/21/should-you-get-a-credit-card-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[itsmesanjo@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 09:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benefits of credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit cards india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creditcard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indian credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Should you]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/?p=5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Before we get into the crux of the question let me push out the basics. What is a Credit card? A credit card is technically very similar to debit card and the main difference being you are not paying upfront the amount you shopped for, more like a &#8220;Buy Now Pay Later&#8221; policy. Why should&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Before we get into the crux of the question let me push out the basics.</p>



<h3><strong>What is a Credit card?</strong></h3>



<p>A credit card is technically very similar to debit card and the main difference being you are not paying upfront the amount you shopped for, more like a &#8220;Buy Now Pay Later&#8221; policy.</p>



<h3>Why should I use Credit Card?</h3>



<p>Everyone who have opened a bank account will mostly be having their own debit card. Then why would one manage one more card? Now we got into the crux. Here are some benefits of credit card over debit card.</p>



<ol><li><strong>Credit History? CIBIL Score</strong>: In India or around the world, credit card is one of the best ways to create a good Credit History or a CIBIL score), which helps in quick approval of loans such as personal loans or home loans and even to get a better interest rate deal. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, just getting a credit card don&#8217;t get you a good credit score, there are different parameters like how timely you pay your bills, etc.</li><li><strong>Fraud Protection:</strong> If any fraud/ unauthorized transactions occur on your credit card its not your liability (subject to TnC of course). As soon as you encounter one, you should alert your card company to block your card. Rest all the company takes care of, as the money from your end is not lost, its basically the money from the company(in layman terms). Thus the companies gives higher grade of security offerings to this account. Thus it is always better to use credit cards for online transfers.</li><li><strong>Interest Free Period</strong>. Most credit cards provide you interest free period of 45-50 days. Your bills are generated monthly only. Thus even if you buy something now u will mostly have to pay within 20-50 days depending on your date of purchase and billing cycle. If your are using other forms of payment you are losing this amount upfront. In credit cards case, the money is still in your account, which can earn you interest based on your saving account scheme.</li><li><strong>Short Term Loan / No cost EMIs</strong>: Credit Cards also helps if when you are in a Cash Crunch situation and eagerly waiting for salary. In such times you could use your credit card without borrowing money from someone else. For example, if you want to buy your dream phone or those 4k TV, you could use EMI options available, and in some cards No Cost EMIs also, thus less burdening your monthly budget.</li><li><strong>Tracking your monthly expenses</strong>: Credit cards are billed monthly. Thus you receive monthly expense statements which usually equates to your monthly expense if all your expenses were through your credit card.</li><li><strong>Offers/ reward points and more:</strong> Fuel Surcharge waivers, free Airport Lounge access, extra discounts or offers on ecommerce sites these days etc are the cherry on top. Also there are rewards even for paying your credit card bill through apps like Cred. You can use my referral link(<a href="https://app.cred.club/spQx/d18ba9c2">https://app.cred.club/spQx/d18ba9c2</a>) to join Cred</li></ol>



<h3>Is it all sunshine and rainbows?</h3>



<p>Every coin has two sides, credit cards have got their disadvantages too.</p>



<ol><li>Chances of overspending: As money don&#8217;t easily get debited from your bank account it gives a false sense that you are not overspending. It is very important that always consider credit card as another debit card and spend only that much you have kept in your monthly budget for expense.</li><li>Higher Interest Rate and Late Payment fee: Be cautious that after the interest free period the interest rate charged is usually very high. So its very important to pay your credit card bills before the due date in full, otherwise you will end up in a big debt trap and that&#8217;s what Credit card companies want. There is also annual card fees depending on your card, which mostly gets waived off after a particular amount thus urging people to spend more.</li><li>Financial Privacy: These cards come with a undisclosed clause of foregoing your financial privacy, as all your expense history is recorded through your card usage to these companies. Which in turn can we analyzed and used to learn your financial patterns. spending cycle, interests etc. But this is the case with any form of cashless medium. This is one of the main reasons why big conglomerates such as Facebook, Google are after India&#8217;s UPI system and its 1.4 billion market. On the side note privacy is a myth nowadays.</li></ol>



<p>So finally the big question:</p>



<h3>Should you get a credit card?</h3>



<p>The answer is YES, it has lot to offer if you are good with your financial budgeting and NO if you are not.</p>



<p>If you do decide to use credit cards, remember these simple rules:</p>



<ul><li>Keep track of all your purchases.</li><li>Don&#8217;t spend outside your budget.</li><li>Pay off your balance on all of your credit cards at the end of each month.</li><li>Don&#8217;t loan your credit or give out your credit card information to anyone but reliable companies.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/04/21/should-you-get-a-credit-card-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello world!</title>
		<link>https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/04/19/hello-world/</link>
					<comments>https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/04/19/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[itsmesanjo@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 19:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://https://sanjoshaju.github.io/reviewonthings/2021/04/19/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
